Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Papers
1614 - 1880
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Wolcott, Oliver, Jr, 1760-1833.
Collection consists of correspondence (personal and business), federal and state government papers, legal documents, financial papers, speeches and essays, awards and appointments, notes on Wolcott family history, estate papers, and related print material.
29.5 linear feet (59 boxes)
Related Material
An index of catalog cards is available for item level access to Wolcott related material in this and other CHS collections. Access is through writer, recipient and date. The card catalog is located in the Research Center reading room.
Biographical Sketch
Oliver Wolcott, Jr. was born in Litchfield, Connecticut on January 11, 1760. He was the eldest son of Oliver Wolcott (1726-1797) and Laura (Collins) Wolcott (1732-1794). After being tutored by his mother he entered the town grammar school to prepare for Yale College, and immediately after graduation in 1778, he studied law under Tapping Reeve. He served in the military during the American Revolution as a volunteer in two minor campaigns in 1777 and 1779. He accepted an appointment in the quartermaster's department and supervised the safekeeping and conveyance of army stores and ordnance at Litchfield. He was admitted to the bar in 1781, and he moved to Hartford where he worked in the office of the committee of the pay-table. In January 1782 he was appointed to the Committee of the Pay-Table, and in May 1784 he was appointed a commissioner to adjust and settle the accounts and claims of Connecticut against the United States. In May 1788 he was selected to fill the office of Comptroller of Public Accounts.
In September 1789 Wolcott was appointed auditor of the new federal Treasury, assuming his post in early November. He was appointed by President Washington, on Alexander Hamilton's recommendation, to Comptroller in June 1791. When Hamilton resigned as Secretary of the Treasury, Wolcott was appointed (February 2, 1795) by Washington to succeed him. He served as Treasury Secretary until November 1800, and after a short period as Judge for the Second Circuit Court (1801-1802), he retired from public life.
Wolcott moved with his family to New York in 1803, where he entered into a business partnership with James Watson, Moses Rogers, Archibald Gracie, and William Woolsey. This group of businessmen formed a commission and agency known as Oliver Wolcott & Company. In 1804 his company made its first venture in the China trade, and after the partnership was amicably dissolved at Wolcott's suggestion in April 1805, he concentrated his main energies in that field.
In 1810-1811 Wolcott was elected to the main board of directors of the Bank of the United States, and after the charter lapsed (March 4, 1811) he played a prominent role in the launching of the Bank of America, serving as its president from 1812-1814.
Wolcott returned to Litchfield in 1815, where he set himself up as a gentleman farmer and promoted manufacturing enterprises in the state. He was chosen as candidate for governor by the Toleration Party in 1816, but was defeated by the incumbent, John Cotton Smith. He was elected by a narrow margin in the following year, and served as governor until 1826. A combination of financial setbacks and election defeat caused him to return to New York where he lived with his daughter, Laura Wolcott Gibbs and her husband George.
Oliver Wolcott married Elizabeth Stoughton on June 1, 1785. They had five sons, three of whom died in infancy, and two daughters. Wolcott died in New York City on June 1, 1833.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence (personal and business), federal and state government papers, legal documents, financial papers, business papers (including his papers relating to the China trade, 1805-1814), speeches and essays, awards and appointments, notes on Wolcott family history, estate papers, and related print material. Notable correspondents include John Adams, John Quincy Adams, Fisher Ames, Joel Barlow, Theodore Dwight, Chauncey Goodrich, Alexander Hamilton, Rufus King, Timothy Pickering, Josiah Quincy, Benjamin Tallmadge, Noah Webster, George Washington, and Oliver Wolcott. Included in the collection are the notes of George Gibbs IV for his two volumes Memoirs of the Administrations of Washington and John Adams, Edited from the Papers of Oliver Wolcott, Secretary of the Treasury, 1846.
Arrangement
Materials in this collection are organized into seven series based on Oliver Wolcott, Jr's filing system. Series I: Wolcott's bound volumes, was arranged by Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and placed in 54 bound volumes. The other six series are based on previous archival arrangement. This arrangement follows Wolcott's filing system with some rearrangement over the years and additions of material from other collections.
Series I: Wolcott's bound volumes consists primarily of letters and supporting documents to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. The correspondence was arranged in 54 bound volumes by Oliver Wolcott, Jr. (This series begins with volume 4, as the location of volumes 1 - 3 is not known.) Some of the material has been rearranged by George Gibbs IV. Material has been arranged by correspondent, subject, and/or chronologically. Supporting documents include reports, essays, memoranda, speeches, depositions, interrogations, proposals, proclamations, acts, notes on Wolcott family history, and related print material. The material covers his entire professional career. Notable correspondents include John Adams, John Quincy Adams, Fisher Ames, Joel Barlow, Theodore Dwight, Chauncey Goodridge, Alexander Hamilton, Rufus King, Henry Knox, Timothy Pickering, Josiah Quincy, Benjamin Tallmadge, George Washington, Noah Webster, Eli Whitney, and Oliver Wolcott.
Series II: Correspondence consists primarily of letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and Oliver Wolcott & Company. Items are a mix of personal and business correspondence. Letters addressed to Oliver Wolcott & Co. are interfiled with personal letters and all are filed under Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Some drafts of replies are interfiled with the letters. The majority of these papers appear to have been collected by George Gibbs IV for a biography of Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Later accessions have been randomly interfiled with the original collection. Series includes letters to and from other Wolcott family members including Eliza Wolcott and Frederick Wolcott.
Series III: United States Government appointments consists of material collected by Oliver Wolcott, Jr. while he was employed by the United States Treasury Department and served as a federal Circuit Court judge. Series includes records of accounts, statements, balances, receipts, circular letters and commissions, land valuation, receipts for debentures by members of the Second Congress and Auxiliary Staff, weekly returns of cash and state of balances, record books of the Bank of the United States, Circuit Court papers, and related correspondence. Arrangement is based on previously constructed order.
Series IV: Business papers consists of accounts, receipts, promissory notes, insurance policies, bills of lading, account sales, invoices, statements, packing notes, returns, imports and exports, articles of agreement, cargo abstracts, documents concerning the estate of James Watson, and related correspondence. Series includes business papers from Oliver Wolcott & Co. and the ships Allegany, Triton, Virginia, American Consul, and Trident, and documents and related correspondence concerning the Bank of America, the Bank of the United States, the Phoenix Branch Bank, and the Litchfield Woolen Manufactory.
Series V: Personal papers consists of Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s personal papers including his official appointments and honorary degrees, legal papers, mortgages, real estate transactions, receipts, promissory notes, bills, invoices, accounts, deduction of titles, deeds, summons, drafts of speeches, letters and jottings, and related correspondence.
Series VI: Connecticut Offices consists of papers generated during Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s years working in a variety of Connecticut state offices. Executive papers include speeches, correspondence (drafts and copies), general orders, proclamations, jottings, legal depositions, indentures, documents from the Supreme Court of Errors and related print material. Other state papers include material collected while Wolcott was Assistant Deputy Quartermaster for Litchfield and Comptroller of Public Accounts.
Series VII: Wolcott family papers consists of papers of the Wolcott family including those of Henry Wolcott, George Gibbs, John Stoughton, Oliver Wolcott, and Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Series includes business and legal papers, diplomas, indentures, licenses of agreements, estate inventories, family deeds, and related correspondence.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection. Some material is fragile so the researcher is initially directed to microfilm copies
Accruals
The collection is open, but additional material is not expected.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Goodrich, Chauncey; Parsons, Samuel Holden; Putnam, Israel; Sherman, Roger; Trumbull, Jonathan; Ward, Andrew; Washington, George
Subjects
Iroquois Indians Treaties.; Lexington, Battle of, 1775.; Concord, Battle of, 1775.
Geographic Names
United States History Revolution, 1775-1783 Prisoners, Exchange of.; United States History Revolution, 1775-1783 Secret service.
Genre Forms
Holographs; holographs, signed; printed forms completed in manuscript.
Contents:
- I. Wolcott's Bound Volumes
  - Vol. 4. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., December, 1782 - March, 1783; (12 items) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 4. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., April - December, 1783; (10 items) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 4. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1784; (14 items) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 4. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1785; (9 items) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 4. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1786; (12 items) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 4. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1787; (14 items) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 4. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1789 - 1790; (11 items) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 4. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1791; (10 items) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 4. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1791 - 1792; (6 items) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 4. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1793; (17 items) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 4. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1794; (16 items) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 5. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1795; (14 items) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 5. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., January - June, 1796; (13 items) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 5. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., July - December, 1796; (10 items) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 5. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Wolcott., 1797; (5 items) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 5. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Chauncey Goodrich., 1789 - 1790; (6 items) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vol.5. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Chauncey Goodrich., 1791 - 1793; (17 items) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 5. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Chauncey Goodrich., 1794 - 1798; (12 items) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Vol.5. Letters to and from Chauncey Goodrich and Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1799 - 1801; (14 items) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 5. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Chauncey Goodrich., 1803 - 1808; (14 items) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 6. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Rufus King., 1795 - 1802; (15 items) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 6. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from James W. Henry., 1797 - August, 1800; (8 items) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 6. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from James W. Henry., September - December, 1800; (12 items) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 6. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Timothy Pickering, James McHenry, Rufus King, and Thomas Evans., 1800 - 1803; (6 items) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 6. Letters to and from Roger Griswold and Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1802 - 1804; (16 items) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 6. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Stephen Higginson., 1798 - 1799; (15 items) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 6. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from John Davis., 1796 - 1798; (9 items) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 6. Letters with supporting documents to and from Jonathan Dayton and Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Draft of letter from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. to Governor St. Clair., 1796 - 1800; (11 items) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 6. Letters to and from Noah Webster and Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1795 - 1801; (6 items) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 6. Letters with supporting documents to and from Timothy Pickering and Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1798 - 1800; (5 items) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 6. Letters to George Cabot from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1800 - 1803; (6 items) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 6. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1793 - 1808; (6 items) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Vol. 7. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Alexander Hamilton., 1794 - 1795; (19 items) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 7. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Alexander Hamilton., January - July, 1796; (11 items) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 7. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Alexander Hamilton., August - December, 1796; (13 items) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 7. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Alexander Hamilton., 1797 - 1798; (18 items) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 7. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Alexander Hamilton., 1799 - 1803; (15 items) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 7. Letters and supporting documents concerning Alexander Hamilton., July, 1804; (15 items) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 7. Letters and supporting documents to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. concerning Alexander Hamilton., July - August, 1804; (11 items) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 7. Letters and copies of letters from Alexander Hamilton., 1791; (5 items) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 8. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Jedidiah Morse., 1791 - 1795; (12 items) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 8. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Jedidiah Morse., 1796 - 1799; (15 items) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 8. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Jedidiah Morse., 1800; (7 items) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 8. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Timothy Dwight and David Ely., 1793 - 1808; (4 items) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 8. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Noah Webster, Jr., 1793 - 1800; (11 items) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 8. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Noah Webster, Jr., 1801 - 1808; (4 items) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 8. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Oliver Ellsworth., 1795 - 1800; (8 items) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 8. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from John Trumbull., 1792 - 1795; (10 items) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 8. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from John Trumbull., 1796 - 1804; (12 items) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Vol. 8. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from William Smith., 1795 - 1799; (8 items) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 8. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from William Vans Murray., 1795; (8 items) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 9. Letters and supporting documents to and from George Washington and Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1793 - June, 1796; (10 items) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 9. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from George Washington., July, 1796 - 1798; (11 items) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 9. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from John Adams., 1795 - 1797; (15 items) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 9. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from John Adams., 1798 - April, 1799; (13 items) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 9. Letters and supporting documents to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and John Adams and William Shaw., May - December, 1799; (14 items) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 9. Letters with supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from John Adams., 1800; (11 items) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 9. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and John Adams., 1801 - 1823; (3 items) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 9. Regulations concerning the Island of St. Domingo and Instructions to.. .Envoys.. .of the United States of America to the French Republic., 1799; (2 items) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 10. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1783 - 1784; (2 items) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 10. Letters with supporting documents to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and Andrew Kingsbury and Ralph Pomeroy., 1791 - 1792; (7 items) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 10. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. while he was Secretary of the Treasury., 1795; (8 items) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 10. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. while he was Secretary of the Treasury., 1796; (17 items) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 10. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. while he was Secretary of the Treasury., 1797 - 1798; (15 items) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 10. Letters and supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. while he was Secretary of the Treasury., 1799; (5 items) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 10. Letters and supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. while he was Secretary of the Treasury., 1800; (4 items) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Vol. 10. Letters with supporting documents to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1801; (5 items) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Vol.10. Letters to Alexander Hamilton while he was Secretary of the Treasury., 1789 - 1790; (6 items) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 10. Letters to and from Alexander Hamilton., 1791 - 1792; (6 items) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 10. Letters to and from Alexander Hamilton with supporting Treasury Department documents., 1783 - 1793; (5 items) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 11. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Joel Barlow, including one letter from Ruth Barlow., 1779 - 1791; (13 items) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 11. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Joel Barlow., 1792 - 1797; (11 items) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 11. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Lemuel Hopkins and Edward Jones., 1783 - 1795; (11 items) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 11. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and John Trumbull., 1789 - 1800; (7 items) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 11. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. from Benjamin Goodhue., 1793 - 1803; (12 items) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 11. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1788 - 1825; (16 items) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 11. Depositions and interrogatories concerning the fires in the War Office and Treasury Building., 1800 - 1801; (3 items) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 11. Comptroller's Office report to Alexander White, Chairman of a Committee of the House of Representatives (Feb. 1792); Statement of what has been done since the establishment of the present government respecting the Lands of the United States in the Territory North-West of the Ohio (Dec. 1800)., 1792 - 1800; (2 items) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 11. Items relating to Treasury Department business., 1798 - 1813; (5 items) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 11. Copy of Henry Knox's Report on the expediency of further retaining West Point as a military post., 1786; (1 item) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 11. Proposal for Raising a Fund on the whole Trade and Shipping of the Port of London, for the support of the Marine Police Establishment., 1799; (1 items) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 11. Translation of letter to Alexander Hamilton from Baron von Steuben; printed documentation concerning Baron von Steuben's compensation for service in the Revolutionary War., 1776 - 1785; (3 items) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 12. Reports and supporting documents to the House of Representatives, Senate, and the President from the Secretary of the Treasury., 1800; (9 items) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Vol. 12. Draft of Report to the President of the United States relative to the execution of the 6th article of the Treaty of Amity, July 11, 1799., 1799 - 1814; (2 items) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 12. Drafts of reports and supporting documents from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1800; (4 items) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 12. Correspondence and drafts of reports on the subjects of treaties with Great Britain. Drafts of reports and related correspondence to the President and House of Representatives concerning citizens' petitions., 1800; (13 items) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 12. Letters and supporting documents concerning the Treasury Department., 1800; (4 items) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 12. Treasury Department reports and confidential papers., 1785? - 1793?; (5 items) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 12. Correspondence and supporting documents concerning Treasury Department business and relations with France., 1793 - 1798; (8 items) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 12. Correspondence and supporting documents concerning Treasury Department business and relations with France., 1796 - 1800; (12 items) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 13. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. including a number concerning the Yellow Fever Epidemic in Philadelphia., 1791 - 1796; (14 items) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Vol.13. Letters primarily to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Some letters concern the Whiskey Rebellion and Eli Whitney and the cotton gin., 1794; (18 items) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 13. Letters primarily to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Some items concern relations with Native Americans., 1795; (19 items) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 13. Letters and supporting documents to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1773 - 1782; (4 items) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 14. Letters primarily to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., January - June, 1796; (20 items) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 14. Letters primarily to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., July - December, 1796; (18 items) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 14. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., January - June, 1797; (13 items) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 14. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., July - December, 1797; (20 items) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 14. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., January - June, 1798; (21 items) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 14. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., July - December, 1798; (24 items) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 15. Letters, primarily applications for office, to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., January - June, 1799; (18 items) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 15. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., July, 1799; (13 items) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 15. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., August, 1799; (11 items) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 15. Letters with supporting print material to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., September, 1799; (13 items) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 15. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., October - December, 1799; (13 items) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 15. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. One letter dated 1801., January - June, 1800; (13 items) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Vol.15. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and Elizabeth Wolcott., July, 1800; (9 items) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 15. Letters with supporting documents to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., August - September, 1800; (21 items) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 15. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., October - November, 1800; (11 items) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 15. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. One letter dated August, 1800., December, 1800; (11 items) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 16. Political. List of correspondents in volume 16., 1801 - 1803; (1 item) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 16. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1801; (18 items) (Box 8, Folder 2)